

https://alkasood.github.io/ alkasood986@gmail.com +91- 99884 47533

Self-disciplined and meticulous User Interface (UI) and User Experience (UX) Designer with 6 years of professional experience. Possesses strong analytical and User-Centred design skills to create holistic solutions that are functional and research-driven.

COURSES

Google - UX Design Professional Certificate

// January 2022 - June 2022, Online - In progress

Udemy - Learning Axure RP8 - UX Design Fundamentals Completed //December 2021, Online

Udemy - Learn Figma - UI/UX Design Essential Training Completed //July 2020, Online

LinkedIn - Adobe XD for Designers Certification Completed //April 2020, Online

PCWD(Web Designing) Certification of Accomplishment //April 2010 - Adreno, Chandigarh

EXPERIENCE

Konceive Development Centre Pvt. Ltd, Panchkula

Web Designer | February 2021 till now

Technologies Working On:

HTML, CSS, SASS, GitLab, Material UI, PHP, Figma, Adobe XD, Photoshop, Primevue Framework, Jquery with beginner level.

Responsibilities:

- 1. Design the aesthetics to be implemented within a product.
- 2. Update the current code as per the business requirements.
- 3. Build reusable code and libraries for future use, ensuring the technical feasibilities of UX/UI Designs.
- 4. Worked with developers in key stages of the design process.
- 5. Experience working in an Agile/Scrum development process as well as GIT Lab.
- 6. Designing wireframe for independent modules.
- 7. Provided front-end developers finalized, detailed design specifications including assets for direct implementation.
- 8. Designed and created user-centric projects throughout the entire product lifecycle; kept track of performance and

- potential technical issues.
- 9. Training Latest Technologies to Team (Responsive Websites, Frameworks)
- 10. Collaborated closely with cross-functional teams.
- 11. Designing assistance with Python team.
- 12. Understanding of interface design processes and frameworks

Cube InfoTech, Chandigarh

Sr. UI/UX Designer | August 2020 to February 2021

Technologies Worked On:

Shopify HTML, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap, WordPress, Photoshop, Wireframes, and Figma. Jquery

Responsibilities:

- 1. Implementing user-centred design, mobile optimized sites and mobile apps designing within pre-set budgets and deadlines.
- 2. Develop UI mock-ups and prototypes that clearly illustrate how sites function and look like.
- 3. Identify and troubleshoot UX problems (e.g. responsiveness)
- 4. Understanding client needs, requirements, and expectations and devise solutions accordingly.
- 5. Quote discussions with BD team, estimating quote for projects.
- 6. Implementation of new technologies in team
- 7. Developing websites in Shopify.
- 8. Creating responsive websites independently.

Web World Experts, Chandigarh

Team Lead | February 2014 to November 2014

Responsibilities:

- 1. Develops wireframes, site maps, schematics, flowcharts, working prototypes, creates designs based on client specifications and documents user experience.
- 2. Implementing projects plans within pre-set budgets and deadlines.
- 3. Collaborates closely with the app development team to bring prototypes into the production code process.
- 4. Implements user-centred/ focused designs and processes in order to identify specific user needs and find best solutions.
- 5. Coordinates tasks with product, front-end developers, and manual testers in order to ensure all products are developed to accurately meet client objectives.
- 6. Conducted, planned, and synthesized user research for use of web and app development team.
- 7. Understanding client needs, requirements, and expectations and devise solutions accordingly.
- 8. End to End Project Delivery from Design Phase.
- 9. Quote discussions with BD team, estimating quote for projects.
- 10. Implementation of new technologies in team creating templates of approved website layout, Training Juniors.

11. Handling Team Experienced in creating websites and UI development for handheld devices like Smartphone's (iPhone, Android and Tablets)

Cogniter Technology, Chandigarh

Assistant Team Lead | October 2012 to February 2014

Technologies Worked On:

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Photoshop, Wireframe, Responsive Layout.

Responsibilities:

- 1. Prepared research to keep track on all trends and developments in various industries; identified the capabilities that should be adopted in the design/ building process.
- 2. Endeavoured to turn complicated processes and concepts into user-friendly, highly-intuitive, and navigable interfaces.
- 3. Created mock-up user interfaces to be used as reference points prior to finalizing the specifications and requirements..
- 4. Worked with developers in key stages of the design process.
- 5. Designing wireframe for website layouts
- 6. Provided front-end developers finalized, detailed design specifications including assets for direct implementation.
- 7. Designed and created user-centric projects throughout the entire product lifecycle; kept track of performance and potential technical issues.
- 8. Training Latest Technologies to Team (Responsive Websites, Frameworks)
- 9. Collaborated closely with cross-functional teams.
- 10. Presided over design-focused meetings with clients.

Cerulean Technology, Bangalore.

Web Designer | June2011 to October 2012

Technologies Worked On:

HTML, CSS, Bootstrap, Joomla, Magneto, Photoshop, Wireframes.

Responsibilities:

- 1. Responsible for the Design, layout mock-ups.
- 2. Designing wireframe for website layouts
- 3. Coding, Mock-ups, Designing assets (Logos, Banners and images), and modifying and enhancing photos

AARYAA & ASSOCIATES, Chandigarh

Graphic Designer | April,2010 to May 2011

SKILLS

Technical

Figma // Adobe XD // Adobe Photoshop // Axure RP // HTML // CSS-SASS // Basic knowledge of GitLab // Basic Jquery

Design

User research // WI reframing // Prototyping // Usability studies // Presentations

Collaboration

Good Communication // Strong presenter // Team player

EDUCATION

Post- Graduation in Master of Computer Application //Lovely Professional University, Jalandhar - May 2009

Graduation in Bachelor in Computers //Khalsa College, Amritsar - July 2006

Post-Matriculation in Non-Medical //Khalsa College, Amritsar - July 2003

Matriculation

//Dalhousie Hill Top School, Dalhousie - May 2001

PERSONAL

Husband Name: Mr Ankit Sood Date of Birth: 10.01.1986 Marital Status: Married

Language: English, Hindi, Punjabi

Nationality: Indian

Current Location: Zirakpur.

DECLARATION:

I hereby declare that above statement are true to the best of my knowledge and belief.

Alka Sood